Kimberly Maloney, M.Ed.

26691 Lippert Road • Cochranton, PA 16314 814-439-0119 • kimbersue 10@gmail.com

Objective:

Highly qualified English Teacher and Reading Specialist with over three years of teaching experience at both the middle and secondary level. In possession of a Master of Education in Middle and Secondary English 7-12, as well as a Master of Education in Reading, with a Reading Specialist K-12 Certification. In search of a teaching position which will allow me to utilize my experience as an English teacher and/or a Reading Specialist.

Education:

Master of Education in Reading Reading Specialist Certification

5/2016

Edinboro University of Pennsylvania, Edinboro, PA

GPA: 3.9

Master of Education in Middle and Secondary Education Certification in English 7-12

5/2010

Edinboro University of Pennsylvania, Edinboro, PA GPA 3.77

Bachelor of Arts in English Literature

12/2005

Edinboro University of Pennsylvania, Edinboro, PA Graduated with Latin Honors—Cum Laude

GPA: 3.53

Teaching Experience:

High School Language Arts Teacher (Ninth Grade)

8/2012 - 6/2013

Hampton High School, Hampton, VA

- Integrated various forms of technology, including Mac Laptops, Podcasts, GarageBand, Promethean Board, etc. in order to aid student comprehension and promote engagement
- Instructed students individually and in groups, established clear objectives and used a variety of teaching methods such as lectures, discussions, cooperative learning, and modeling
- Adapted materials and differentiated instruction for English Language Learners (ELLs) and students with Individual Educational Plans (IEPs)
- Adopted a proactive approach to managing student behavior through clear expectations and engaging lessons

Middle School Language Arts Teacher (Seventh Grade)

7/2011-5/2012

Tartesso Elementary School, Buckeye, AZ

- Provided instruction centered on reading comprehension strategies, helped increase Seventh Grade average reading score on Benchmark Exam by 15% during First Quarter (57% to 72%)
- Encouraged socializing with peers and discussions about literature, while also promoting independent reading, through the creation of a seventh grade book club
- Collaborated with Social Studies Teacher to create a cross-curricular unit for students
- Utilized Accelerated Reader (AR) as a tool to motivate students to read through gaining points and rewards for meeting their individual goals
- Utilized classroom data in order to improve lesson planning in and provide remediation where it was needed
- Promoted improvement of reading comprehension through explicit instruction and modeling of research based instructional strategies

Summer School Teacher

6/2016 - 7/2016

Titusville Area School District (Grant through YMCA), Titusville, PA

- Promoted student comprehension by connecting student's prior knowledge to lesson at hand
- Provided students with effective instruction through use of modeling and other research based instructional strategies
- Developed daily lesson plans that motivated and engaged middle school students in their learning
- Promoted classroom community and differentiated instruction through heterogeneous cooperative learning groups

Substitute Teacher

12/2010-6/2011 &

Kelly Services, Crawford County, PA

12/2015-Present

- Employs instructional methods and materials that are appropriate for meeting lesson objectives
- Creates a classroom environment that is conducive to learning and appropriate to the maturity and interests of the students
- Guides the learning process toward the achievement of curriculum goals and objectives as indicated in the lesson plans for the lessons, units, or projects assigned
- Maintains a professional and positive rapport with parents, co-workers, and administration

Long-Term Language Arts Substitute (Ninth Grade)

8/2010 - 11/2010

Meadville Area Senior High School, Meadville, PA

- Created high interest lessons to motivate and engage students in their learning
- Utilized grade-level curriculum to establish a timeline and meet instructional goals
- Established rules and procedures for proactive management of classroom behavior

Additional Work Experience:

GED/Diploma Instructor

8/2016 - Present

Titusville Regional Literacy Council, Titusville, PA

- Utilize curricula that reflect the diverse educational, cultural, and linguistic backgrounds of the students served
- Teach basic skills encompassing math, science, social studies, and language arts
- Instruct students on material needed in order to earn their GED, as well as assist them in earning their high school diploma through the completion of a diploma project
- Integrate competencies, goals, and objectives into lesson plans

Assistant Softball Coach

2/2012 - 5/2012

Tartesso Elementary School, Buckeye, AZ

- Conditioned and trained students to be physically fit to play softball
- Instructed students regarding important softball rules that they must know and follow
- Coached softball players on basic batting and fielding skills, and how to correctly run bases

Activities:

Professional Affiliations:

- National Education Association (NEA)
- National Council of Teachers of English (NCTE)
- Association for Middle Level Education (AMLE)